# Mengyi Gong

256 Webster Ave, Jersey City, NJ 07307

(201)912-9569

Email: mgong1@stevens.edu

#### Summary & Objective

Master Degree in Computer Science. Innovational Software Developer with great experience in web programming, UX/UI design and Testing. Pursue a challenging career in Software development.

Specialties: Web Programming, Front-end, UI/UX Design, Android, Unit Testing and Agile Process

#### Work Experience

Micro Technology Company Shenzhe

Shenzhen, China May 2013 - Aug. 2013

Android UX/UI Development Intern

- Designed and developed the layout of a video application using Android SDK and Eclipse.
- Assisted senior developers with Unit Testing on the mobile application by using JUnit testing framework.

#### Eastern Washington University WA, USA Aug. 2011 - Jan. 2012

Teaching Assistant - Computer Science Department

- Taught C, C#, Java programming in the computer lab of EWU.
- Tutored the undergraduates to solve problems within their projects regarding.

# Projects

**EAccount** Apr. 22 2014 - May. 12 2014

- Design and develop a banking system for personal use by Bootstrap (HTML5 CSS3), JavaScript, Jquery, Node.js and MangoDb. Using Photoshop design the pictures and logo.
- Different user could log in to their personal account by using **Ajax**, and they can switch among personal info setting, account view, alter line setting, calendar and account note view tags. And also set the cookie.
- The entire account summary will show as dynamic graphic (bar chart, pan chart and line chart) to clear show the spending (by category, time), income and the overall view.

# Multi-Channel Chat Mar. 24 2014 - Mar. 25 2014

- Design and develop a chat room by using socket.io Framework and NodeJS and HTML5/CSS3.
- Different user could log in to see all users and all chat rooms by using Ajax

#### Foodie Aug. 2013 – Dec. 2013

- Design and develop the front-end of the system using JavaScript, JQuery, Google Map API, Boostrap Framework and HTML5/CSS3.
- Integrated the system with a web service using RESTful call and fetched data by parsing JSON flows.

# Medical Information System in Cloud (AWS) Aug. 2013

- Designed and implemented Domain Model, Persistence Layer, and Data Access Layer with design patterns.
- Conducted Data Modeling including XML Schemas, object-relational modeling (ORM).
- Established the Linux, Glassfish, and PostgreSQL environment on the Amazon EC2.
- Implemented SOAP Web Services and deploy it on EC2. Developed a client application using the web services WSDL.

# HTTP Web Server Feb. 2013 - May. 2013

- Developed a HTTP web server using C under the Linux environment.
- Implemented the functionalities to handle requests from Browser through HTTP operations.

# College Students' Physical Examination and Health Evaluation Management System Jan. 2012 - July. 2012

 Programed Java application to gather, manage and analyze the results of students' physical examinations. Implement the front-end of the system using *HTML*, *CSS*, and *Javascript*.

# Maze video game board March. 2011 - June. 2011

- Implemented a maze video game borad with VGA output and PS/2 keyboard input based on Xilinx Spartan 2 FPGA and Verilog.
- Implemented LED digital tube on the FPGA board to display remaining time. Installed multifunctional buttons for inputting time limit and selecting maze maps.

#### Education

Stevens Institute of Technology Baster of Science in Computer Science Aug. 2012 – May. 2014

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sept. 2008 – May. 2012

# **Honor & Awards**

Outstanding Graduate Scholarship, awarded by EWU June, 2012

#### IT Skills

Languages: Java, C/C++, JavaScript/JQuery, HTML5/CSS3, PHP, SQL and UNIX Shell Scripting

IDE: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Photoshop cs6 Database: Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL, MongodDB and PostgreSQL.

Framework: Boostrap, Junit, NodeJS